syntelinc.com 2015-05-29

# Privacy Policy | Syntel - IT Consulting | IT Outsourcing Services | BPO/KPO | Enterprise Solutions

Privacy Policy _[Effective Date: 04/10/2015]_

Syntel respects and is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy applies to our publicly available website [ syntelinc.com](http://www.syntelinc.com/ "Syntel, Inc.") and the various publicly available subdomains thereof, owned and operated by Syntel, Inc. ("Syntel", "We", "Us"). This privacy policy describes how Syntel collects and uses the personal information you provide on our website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. You can view our website without divulging any personal information other than your Internet Protocol (IP) address, however certain content on our website requires registration and the transmittal of additional personal information.

 **U.S.—E.U. and U.S—Swiss Safe Harbor**

Syntel, Inc. complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Syntel, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Syntel, Inc.’s certification, please visit [ http://www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor) .

 **Information Collection and Use**

For example, we may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, and phone number
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name and job title
  * Demographic information such as education, gender, ethnicity and citizenship status

We may collect such personal information when you:

  * Submit contact form(s) on our website
  * Post comment(s) to our blog
  * Subscribe to our email alerts and/or newsletter
  * Request printed materials to be sent to you in hardcopy
  * Send us your resume via our website

We may use this information to:

  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Send you a newsletter or email alerts
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Process a job application
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our website and marketing efforts

 **Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell, trade, or rent personal information to any outside person or organization.

Service Providers

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service, hosting our website or processing emails. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Legal Disclaimer

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * if Syntel is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information; and
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

 **User Access and Choice**

You may correct, update, amend, or request deletion of your information by emailing our Customer Support at [ privacy@syntelinc.com](mailto:privacy@syntelinc.com "Privacy Policy") or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please submit your request in an email to [ privacy@syntelinc.com](mailto:privacy@syntelinc.com "Privacy Policy") .

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

 **Tracking Technologies / Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this website. However, we do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our website.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires and is automatically deleted when you close your browser. When the user logs in to the website a new session cookie will be generated, which will store the user’s browsing information and will be active until the user leaves the website and closes the browser.

When the user restarts the browser and goes back to the website that had created the cookie, the website will not recognize the user. The user will have to log back in (if login is required). A session cookie tracks visitor behavior from page to page so the visitors don't get asked repeatedly for the same information they had already given to the website. Session cookies allow users to proceed through many pages of a website quickly and easily without having to authenticate or reprocess each new area they visit. We are not using the information stored in session cookies for any other purpose nor are these shared with third party tools or websites.

A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. These files stay in one of the browser's subfolders until these are deleted manually or the browser deletes them based on the duration period specified within the persistent cookie. Persistent cookies help websites remember user information and settings when they visit them in the future. This results in faster and more convenient browsing during subsequent visits. Some of the features made possible by persistent cookies include: language selection, theme selection, menu preferences, and internal site bookmarks or favorites, among many others. We are not using the information stored in persistent cookies for any other purpose nor are these shared with third party tools or websites. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s "help" menu. If you configure your Internet browser to reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some areas of our website will be limited.

 **Web Beacons / Gifs**

Third party tracking technologies on our website may employ a software technology called clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons) that help us better manage content on our website by informing us what content is effective. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of website users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We are using analytics programs such as Google® Analytics and PardotTM. We do not tie the information gathered by clear GIFs to our visitors’ personally identifiable information, except for IP address. This information is used only for analytical purpose.

 **Analytics / Log Files**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically through analytics programs such as Google Analytics and Pardot, and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users beyond their IP address, to analyze trends, to administer the website, to track users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

 **Third Party Tracking**

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other third party assets (such as Google Analytics and Pardot) on the website is not covered by our privacy policy. These third parties may use cookies, clear GIFs, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our website. We do not have access or control over these technologies. We do not tie the information gathered to our customers’ or users’ personally identifiable information.

 **Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting**

We may partner with a third party ad network to display advertising on our website and to manage our advertising on other websites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information (except potentially IP address) about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [ clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "Unsubscribe") . Please note, this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

 **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. Syntel maintains the international Standard IS/ISO/IEC 27001 on "Information Technology – Security Techniques – Information Security Management System – Requirement" Organizations can choose to comply with this information security management system that contains managerial, technical, operational and physical security control measures that are commensurate with the information assets being protected and with the nature of our business. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

 **Additional Information**

 **Links to Third Party Websites**

Syntel may provide links to Internet websites maintained by others. Syntel is not responsible for the contents of, or any products or services offered in, those third party websites. You should be aware when you are leaving Syntel's website and be sure to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. Any links provided by Syntel to any third party website are provided to you as a convenience only. You should not infer that Syntel endorses or accepts responsibility for non-Syntel websites by the inclusion of any such links to those websites.

 **Blog / Forum**

Our website may make message boards, forums, chat rooms, and/or news groups available to its users. Please understand that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information. These areas shall be used in a noncommercial manner only. Except where expressly authorized by Syntel, you agree not to store or collect data about other users on our website.

 **Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook® like button, links to our social media pages and widgets, such as the AddThis® button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

 **Changes To This Policy**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our privacy practices. If we make any material changes we may notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

 **Contact Us**

 **General Inquiries:**

You can reach Syntel through postal mail, phone or fax

Attn: Syntel Privacy Officer

Syntel, Inc.   
525 E. Big Beaver   
Third Floor   
Troy, MI 48083   
United States   
tel: +1-248-619-2800   
fax: +1-248-619-2888

In case of any grievance, please email [ privacy@synelinc.com](mailto:privacy@synelinc.com) or contact Mr. Sandeep Godbole at [ Sandeep_Godbole@syntelinc.com](mailto:Sandeep_Godbole@syntelinc.com) . Grievances shall be redressed as expeditiously as possible.

 _If a privacy complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through Syntel’s internal process, Syntel has agreed to participate in the VeraSafe EU Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Procedure for U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor disputes. To file a complaint with the Procedure, please submit the required information to VeraSafe here:[ https://www.verasafe.com/dispute-submission](https://www.verasafe.com/dispute-submission "VeraSafe Dispute Submission") ._

 _Syntel regularly reviews its compliance with this privacy policy. When we receive formal written complaints, it is Syntel’s policy to contact the complainant regarding his or her concerns. Syntel will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, in their investigation of any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between Syntel and an individual._
